<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Alestrio</title><link>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Alestrio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Low Level C and Assembly development environment with VSCode and WSL2</title><link>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/wsl_vscode_dev_environment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/wsl_vscode_dev_environment/</guid><description>As a Computer Science Engineering student, I recently had to complete an exercise involving assembly programming on Linux. To make my workflow as efficient and productive as possible, I set up a low-level C and assembly development environment using Visual Studio Code (VSCode) and Windows Subsystem for Linux 2 (WSL2). The goal, was to be able to edit assembly code, but also run and debug it as if I was programming on Windows.</description></item><item><title>Easily install an OpenVPN server</title><link>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/easy_openvpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/easy_openvpn/</guid><description>A VPN is a tunnel that is completely opaque to the outside world and allows two distinct physical networks to be joined. The technical applications of a VPN are multiple:
Access to corporate resources on a remote site Securing information exchanges between two networks Online gaming: to secure a game server Anonymity and confidentiality: protect personal data by relocating users Telecommuting : access to company resources from home &amp;hellip; Normally, setting up a VPN server requires advanced network and system knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Create a static website with Github Pages and Hugo</title><link>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/static_personnal_site/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/static_personnal_site/</guid><description>During the last two years, I studied Networks and Telecommunications at the IUT of Châlons-en-Champagne. Among the skills I acquired, there are, of course, technical skills but also communication skills.
During my third year project, I was asked to replace the traditional paper project report by a static website, whose vocation was also to serve as a documentation of the project production.
In this case, to convey a message, it&amp;rsquo;s not the point to make an ultra well done website, with animations everywhere but very heavy.</description></item><item><title>Bookeen Notéa Review</title><link>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/bookeen_notea_review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.alexislebel.fr/en/blog/bookeen_notea_review/</guid><description>The French electronic notepad Introduction It will be nearly two years that I am in university studies at the IUT of Châlons-en-Champagne. Since the beginning of my studies, I used tons of papers, of which only a few traces remain at home.
I always wanted to get rid of this way of doing things, which is as costly in natural resources as in money, space and time. Indeed, once my course is written on a sheet of paper that required cutting down trees, it has to be put away, then stored.</description></item></channel></rss>